okay I've got a very tired strength and
conditioning coach Keith sniping here he
just finished a glute workout this is
the second time doing it at my garage
and I just wanted to film him and ask
him about his impressions so go ahead
keep well I really enjoy the exercises I
think that they have a huge huge value
as assistants moves for speed and power
athletes obviously for physique people
it's a sort of a no-brainer that if you
can overload your glutes with some of
those exercises like the different
variations and the hip thrusts the
single Mike scores your exercises like
Oakland like hip extension and you're
going to get some pretty good glute
activation for me I'm looking at it for
improving my sprinting performance
because I had I think a lack of glute
activation in my sprint cycle do the
problem to have with my feet believe my
toes and I'm really not able to get that
full triple extension here I leave a lot
cut on cable and I don't get that full
glutes I feel like I really don't know
how to use my glute well from this
position that the pendulum exercises
with the reverse hyper I thought we were
really tough especially with a very
light load up that I was using it was
taught to stabilize my spine so that
told me right there that's a huge core
stabilization exercise as well be able
to control your college while you're
getting an active hit hip extension
which I have a hard time getting so
either someone has healthy feet so that
you can get those end range of motion
that's not extra pot without paper
sitting your spine Tim be a little
extension there has to be there's just
no way that that's not going to be some
sort of cows to improve your performance
on them I'm definitely so
Francis is doing kind of like her first
leg press back in the 80s and I think
you just kind of taking some of that
stuff taking it to like hold it alone so
I'm you know I'm very excited about
trying to incorporate these into my my
spreading program if I could replace my
house we're going to squat so I'm going
to deadlift you know throw a hand clean
maybe your power snatches with
kettlebells dumbbells you know I do a
lot of med ball throws I really see how
these are going to fit into my program
just give me a lot more focused on my
hips on a hip-hop that hip extension
that I'm really not getting especially
in my sprint so with this and all the
training under the course if i get my
times lower and you know I've actually
got fixed the issues of having my my big
toes and jacking up my achilles tendons
but think if i can give those under
control I'm really saying if I can take
a good second plus out my time so
definitely very good stuff Keith thinks
a lot back